我们将快速回顾一下三角函数Tan及其逆。没什么
We're going to do a quick recap on the trigonometric function Tan and its inverse. Nothing on this
到目前为止幻灯片应该让你大吃这是非常标准的高中数学。我们可以
slide so far should surprise you. This is pretty standard high school maths. We can
重新安排它以隔离Tantheta，我们用Y除以X和表示
re-arrange it to isolate Tan theta and we write that in terms of Y divided by X and
那么我们就可以引入逆tan函数，所以我们可以用反函数来写
then we can introduce the inverse tan function, so we can write theta in terms of the inverse
我的X分为Y.
tan of Y divided my X.
反tan函数以许多不同的方式表示，但最常见的是它的写法
The inverse tan function is denoted in many different ways, but most commonly it's written
作为减1的力量的棕褐色，有时它写成棕褐色，有时它是
as tan to the power of minus one, sometimes it’s written as A tan and sometimes it's
写成ArcTan。它们可能是表示反正切的最常用方法
written as Arc Tan. They're perhaps the most common ways of representing the inverse tangent
功能。现在让我们看看一些更复杂的情况，但我们将从最简单的开始
function. Now let's look at some more complex cases, but we'll start off with the simplest
这些案件。我们有一个三角形，它的高度是一个，它的宽度是两个和角度
of these cases. And we have a triangle, its height is one, its width is two and the angle
在三角形中标记的等于0.4636辐亮度。如果我应用逆tan函数
marked in the triangle is equal to 0.4636 radiance. If I apply the inverse tan function
对于两个以上的比例，然后我得到完全相同的值，0.4636。这是正确的
to the ration one over two, then I get exactly the same value, 0.4636. That's right for the
角度为负的情况。在这种情况下，宽度为2，但高度等于-1。
case where the angle is negative. In this case the width is two but the height is equal to minus one.
我可以计算减1除以2的反正切，得到结果
I can compute the arc tangent of minus one divided by two and I get the result which
就像我预期的那样是零下0.4636。现在让我们考虑一个角度的情况
is minus 0.4636 just as I would expect. Now let's consider the case of an angle that's
两个比Pi大。在这种情况下，高度为1，宽度等于-2。
bigger than Pi on two. In this case the height is one and the width is equal to minus two.
在这种情况下，theta等于2.6779辐亮度。如果我计算一个减去的反正切
In this case theta is equal to 2.6779 radiance. If I compute the arc tangent of one over minus
二，然后我得到的结果是负0.4636。我们看到之间存在差异
two, then I get a result which is minus 0.4636. We see that there is a discrepancy between
该直线的实际角度和反正切函数给我们的角度。
the actual angle of this line and the angle that is given to us by the arc tangent function.
同样，对于这种情况，宽度为负2，高度为负1和if
And similarly for this case, the width is minus two, the height is minus one and if
我计算了它的反正切，得到的结果是0.4636。最后的问题
I compute the arc tangent of that, the result I get is 0.4636. The problem in this last
case是负数除以负2，得到的结果与1相同
case is that negative one divided by negative two, gives a result which is the same as one
除以2。这是一个正数，这与我们在该数据中所做的例子相同
divided by two. It's a positive number and that's the same as the example we did at the
从这里开始
beginning up here.
这里的根本问题是反tan函数的范围只有跨越
The underlying problem here is that inverse tan function has got a range which only spans
从减去Pi的两个到加上Pi的两个。为了解决这个问题，我们推出了一个新的
from minus Pi on two to plus Pi on two. To get around the problem we introduce a new
功能，它通常被称为“ATanTwo”，你会在中找到这个名字的功能
function and it's commonly called "A Tan Two", you’ll find a function of this name in the
许多编程语言的数学库，你肯定会在MATLAB中找到它。
mathematical library of many programming languages and you’ll certainly find it in MATLAB.
它考虑了A的符号和B的符号，并且可以从该信息中得到
It takes into account the sign of A and the sign of B and from that information it can
确定角度所在的圆的哪个象限。所以这个功能的范围
determine which quadrant of the circle the angle lies within. So the range of this function
从负Pi到加Pi包括在内。这是一个使用MATLAB计算的简单例子
is from minus Pi to plus Pi inclusive. And here's a simple example using MATLAB, computing
一个除以2的反正切，它给出了2.6779辐射的答案
the arc tangent of one divided by minus two, it gives us the answer of 2.6779 radiance
这是圆圈第二象限的一个角度。
and that's an angle in the second quadrant of the circle.